Guide to the Burdette Keeland Architectural Papers
University of Houston Libraries
Burdette Keeland Architectural Papers
1926-2000
1950-2000
01/2002-005
Keeland, Burdette
25.00 linear feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
The Burdette Keeland Papers cover the period 1926 to 2000 and are comprised of his architectural drawings, business and personal files, memorabilia, photographic prints, and negatives, as well as materials from his teaching career.
Biographical Information:
Burdette Watts Keeland, Jr. was an influential Houston architect. He was well known for his design work, his service as an educator, his long tenure on the City of Houston Planning Commission, and his community involvement with the Park People and other groups.
Keeland was born in Mart, Texas on February 2, 1926, but moved with his family to Houston six months later. He attended Lamar High School, graduating in 1943. He enrolled at Texas A&M University briefly before enlisting in the U.S. Army Air Corps in 1944. He served with U.S. occupation forces in Japan and was discharged in mid 1946. After another short stay at Texas A&M, he enrolled at the University of Houston in the architecture program. In 1947 he married Margaret Scott ("Margie"). From 1950 to 1957 they had four children: Margaret, Burdette III, Ruth, and Bonnie.
Keeland received a Bachelor's degree from the University of Houston in 1950. He began teaching design there in 1954 and was an influential member of the faculty until his death in 2000. He was briefly on the faculty at Rice University and served as lecturer and guest design critic at other noted architecture schools in the United States and Mexico City. Professional organizations recognized Keeland's distinguished teaching career on several occasions. He received outstanding educator awards from the American Institute of Architects, Houston Chapter, in 1987, and the Texas Society of Architects in 1993. In 1992 he was honored at the University of Houston Architecture Alumni Association's Burdette Keeland Roast. In 2000 he was the subject of a retrospective exhibition of his work at the University of Houston's College of Architecture.
His long career at the university was also significant because of his association with Howard Barnstone. An important Houston architect, Barnstone was Keeland's close friend and colleague until Barnstone's death in 1987. In the early 1950s he introduced Keeland to Houston art collectors and philanthropists John and Dominique de Menil and to New York architect Philip Johnson. These relationships had a profound effect on Keeland for the rest of his life. In 1959 Barnstone was also instrumental in Keeland's admission to the graduate architecture program at Barnstone's alma mater, Yale University. Of his many accomplishments, Keeland was perhaps most proud of his role in 1981 to secure for Philip Johnson the commission to design the new building for the College of Architecture. (Among the oversized memorabilia in the collection is the large construction sign for the building, given to Keeland when it was completed.)
In 1964 Mayor Louie Welch appointed Keeland to the Houston Planning Commission. Keeland became chairman in 1981 and served in that capacity until 1991. On January 31 of that year the city honored him by proclaiming the day "Burdette Keeland Day." He was a tireless advocate of the benefits of urban planning, including land-use zoning, a position that was not always popular in the city.
Keeland was a prolific designer and had a successful practice, particularly from 1950 to 1980. Although he never obtained state licensing as an architect, he was well respected by his peers. Over several decades his projects were published consistently in national and international magazines and won a number of design awards.
His career as a designer can be broken into several periods. In the 1950s, influenced by Ludwig Mies van der Rohe and Philip Johnson, Keeland's work followed the Miesian aesthetic of flat-roof pavilions defined by an exposed steel frame. While several examples of this period survive, the best is the Meyerland Parade of Homes House (1955) on Jackwood Street, designed for homebuilder W. K. "Buck" King.
His year at Yale from 1959-60 exposed him to the ideas of other nationally-known architects, such as Paul Rudolph and Louis Kahn. As a result, in the 1960s his work was less predictable, as he explored a number of other approaches to modern architecture. An important example of his work of this decade was his Essex-Houck office building (1961; demolished 1990s), an homage to Louis Kahn.
During the 1970s Keeland moved from architectural design into real estate development, as he adopted the model of a design-build practice. He developed several townhouse complexes in his Kirby Drive-area neighborhood of Houston. They are remarkable for their sensitive scale and relationship to the street. However, his most significant building of this period was the large 4101 Greenbriar office building (1975), which he designed and developed in partnership with other investors.
He also designed the proposed 4141 Greenbriar Building (1983) to be built next door, but Houston's economic depression of the 1980s halted the project. There was little private or commercial construction in the city during this time and Keeland's professional practice suffered. A highlight of the period, however, was his remodeling of his family's residence at 2907 Ferndale St. (1986) with its three-story tower and fanciful supporting column.
In 1986, Keeland suffered a heart attack, the first of a series of health problems to slow him in the last decade of his life. During the 1990s he undertook several residential projects and helped host a number of fund-raisers for the College of Architecture. At two of those, in 1994 and 1998, he welcomed his friend Philip Johnson as guest of honor.
After architecture, Keeland's greatest passion was cemeteries, an interest he developed on a trip to Milan in the late 1960s. There he was inspired by a graveyard filled with interesting and varied funerary monuments. For the rest of his life he studied and documented cemeteries around the world and collected material for a book on the subject, which was never published. He advocated an enlightened approach to these places, suggesting that the living treat them as park space. Keeland invested some of his creative energy in designing headstones and monuments, a number of which were executed for clients. He created a line of designer tombs for a Texas monument company. His largest project was an addition to the Cedarvale Cemetery in Bay City, Texas in the early 1990s. In 1994 his unusual interest earned him feature stories in a number of regional newspapers and a profile in Texas Monthly magazine the following year.
Burdette Keeland, Jr. died on May 26, 2000.
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
University of Houston; University of Houston. Gerald D. Hines College of Architecture
Genre/Form of Material:
Correspondence; Greeting cards; Personal papers; Photographs
Geographic Name:
Houston (Tex.)
Personal Name:
Keeland, Burdette
Topical Term:
Architecture; Architecture, Domestic
Acquisition Information:
The Burdette Keeland Papers were donated to the University of Houston Libraries by Margaret Scott Keeland in 2002.
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Related Materials:
Burdette Keeland Architectural Drawings & Photographs digital collection (http://digital.lib.uh.edu/collection/2002_005)
Harry Walker Photographs digital collection (http://digital.lib.uh.edu/collection/p15195coll17)
Scope and Contents
The Burdette Keeland Papers cover the period 1926 to 2000 and are comprised of his architectural drawings, business and personal files, memorabilia, photographic prints, and negatives, as well as materials from his teaching career. The collection occupies 25 linear feet of shelves and 15 drawers of flat files. It is stored in 40 boxes, 112 oversize folders, and 5 tubes for rolled material. It also includes one oversized construction sign and one piece of framed artwork.
The largest category of documents concerns Keeland's architectural practice. This category is comprised of his architectural drawings, project files, photographs, and magazines in which his work was published. The majority of the original drawings are (a) studies and preliminary drawings and (b) working drawings. Keeland was a talented artist and created presentation drawings in pen and ink for many projects. These are of special interest and are noted in the finding aid for those projects.
Other important categories include Keeland's correspondence files, clippings files, travel photographs, papers from the City of Houston Planning Commission, and files related to his teaching career with the University of Houston.
Also, Keeland amassed an extensive collection of photographic slides of the architecture he encountered on his travels. These slides were separated from the Burdette Keeland Papers and transferred to the Visual Resources Center at the University’s Gerald D. Hines College of Architecture. At present they have not been processed or catalogued.
Detailed List of Contents
- Personal Papers, 1926-2000
  Scope and Contents
  The Personal Papers includes records generally created outside of Keeland’s professional life, such as biographical information, address lists, and material related to his family.
  - Keeland Birth Announcement, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Keeland Obituary, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Keeland Memorial Service Card, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Louise Ferrari Memorial, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - “Mom and Dad”, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Ruth Arnold Keeland, 1922-1990 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Burdette Keeland, Sr., 1900-1965 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
  - Mrs. B.W. Keeland Medical History, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Holmes Trusts, 1967, 1995-2000 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Holmes Family Investments, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Ruth Holmes Lawsuit, 1980-1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Notes on Income, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Check Stubs, 1950-1960 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Friends - Clippings, 1960s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Friends - Telephone Numbers, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Addresses, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 17-20)
  - Name List, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 21-22)
  - Party Talk, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Cards Received, 1960s-1970s (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Cards Received, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Cards Received, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Cards Received, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Cards Received (Illness), 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 28-32)
  - Cards Received (Illness), 1999 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Keeland Thank-you Cards, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Student Postcards, 1960s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Cards and Letters, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 36-41)
  - Burdette’s Gift Cards, 1970s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 42-44)
  - “Stuff for Cards”, 1970s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 45-47)
  - Keeland Art - Inventory, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Keeland Art - Appraisals, Sales, 1992-1993, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Keeland Art - Cards, undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Keeland Art - Receipts, 1981-1998 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Keeland Art - Robert Preusser, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Keeland Art - Dick Wray, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Keeland Art - Forbidden City, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Keeland Art - St. Basil’s Cathedral, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Artwork Correspondence, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Picasso Exhibition Catalog, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Club Posters, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Program, Musical, Hair, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - “Grand Houses” Prospectus, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Professional Papers, 1952-1999
  This section features material related to Keeland’s career as an architectural designer. Folder 9 contains, among other things, a “Self-Employment Statement,” which is Keeland’s own list of his clients and projects from 1951 to 1985. Also notable are his files on other architects, such as Philip Johnson, Howard Barnstone, Buckminster Fuller, and Frank Welch.
  - Vitae and Biographical Material, 1960s (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Vitae and Biographical Material, 1970s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Vitae and Biographical Material, 1990s (Box 2, Folder 3-5)
  - Keeland Biography for Roast, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - “Burdette’s nomination, H.FAIA” (Barnstone file), 1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Board of Architectural Examiners: Keeland, 1965-1985 (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
  - Urban Research, 1969-1972 (Box 2, Folder 10-12)
  - Keeland Stationery, 1960s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 13-14)
  - Keeland Office Brochure, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Keeland Offices - Photographs, 1970s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - BK Speeches, 1965-1995 (Box 2, Folder 17-19)
  - Plywood Design Awards, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Photofest 98 Exhibit, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Texas Society of Architects Meetings - Photographs, 1952, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Rice Design Alliance Awards Dinner - Photographs, 1980s (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Rice Design Alliance, Mies Home Tour, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Houston Architecture - Events, Catalogs, 1970s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 25-26)
  - Office Announcements, 1964-1969 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Architects’ Club, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Telegram, Architectural Forum, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Keeland and Architects - Photographs, 1960s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Eugene Aubry - Clippings, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Howard Barnstone, 1958-1987 (Box 2, Folder 32-36)
  - Howard Barnstone Corespondence, 1957, 1980s (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Barnstone Estate Correspondence, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Howard Barnstone, Proposed Catalog, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Museum of Fine Arts Master Plan, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 40-42)
  - Villa de las Flores Project, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 43-44)
  - Houston Architecture Foundation, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 45-49)
  - Buckminster Fuller Materials, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 50-54)
  - Keeland and Buckminster Fuller, 1960, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Student Paper, Buckminster Fuller, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Keeland and Philip Johnson, 1960s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - “Philip Johnson in New Canaan”, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Frank Welch, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 59-62)
  - Frank Welch Firm Brochure, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Frank Welch C.V., 1996 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Frank Welch Photography, 1995-1998 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Yale Club, 1990s (Box 2, Folder 66-71)
  - Yale Club, 1960s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Lamar High School Reunion, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Texas A&M Alumni Newsletters, 1980s (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Park People Gala, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Cards - Architecture, undated (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - “Photos–Not me”, undated (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Sheet of commemorative architecture postage stamps, undated (Box 2, Folder 78)
- University of Houston, 1940s-2000
  This series contains materials related to Keeland’s long teaching career and his relationship with the University of Houston.
  - UH Job Appointment Letters, 1963-1999 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - UH Job Correspondence, 1958-1989 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - UH Job Correspondence, 1990-2000 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Deanship Application, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 4-6)
  - Deanship Application, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Faculty and Students, 1978–1999 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Letters of Reference, 1980s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Doug Michels Letter, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Harry Ransom Letter, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - College of Architecture, 1950s (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - College of Architecture, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - College of Architecture, 1970s-1992 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - College of Architecture Photographs, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 15-18)
  - College of Architecture Faculty Photographs, 1940s-1970s (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Philip Johnson at UH Photographs, mid 1960s (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - UH Architecture Alumni Association, 1975, 1993-1998 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Johnson and UH Architecture Building - Memo, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Philip Johnson Endowed Chair, 1990, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Groundbreaking, Architecture Building - Scrapbook, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 24-26)
  - Barnstone, Jenkins Eulogies, 1987, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - UH Architecture Society Lecture Series, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Lectures, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Barnstone Lecture Fund, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Ricardo Legoretta Lecture, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Bruce Webb Article, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Peter Blake Lecture, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Atrium Society, 1992-1995 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Annual Fund, College of Architecture, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Keeland Roast - UH Architecture Alumni, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 36-39)
  - Paul Rudolph Fundraiser (S.L.A.B.), 1993 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - “Houston’s Best in Architecture” Fundraiser, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - “Fifty from Fifty” Fundraiser, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - “40 Proof” Lecture, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - “Houston’s Most Interesting” Fundraiser, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Blueprint Ball, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 45-46)
  - “Keeland 2000” Exhibition (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Gerald Hines, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - College of Architecture - Gerald Hines Gift, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Christmas Card, College of Architecture, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Architecture Building/Ledoux Collage, Justin Lau, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Prospectus, Urban Planning Degree, undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Introduction to Architecture Course, 1985, 1990s (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Student Papers About Keeland, 1995-1998 (Box 3, Folder 54-55)
  - AIA Educator Award, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 56-62)
  - TSA Educator Award, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 63-65)
- Business Cards
  Keeland’s large collection of business cards attests to his extensive network of contacts in the local community. The business cards and lists of telephone numbers have been preserved as Keeland left them and have not been separately indexed.
  - Miscellaneous business cards (Box 4, Item 1)
- Audio Recordings, 1953-1968
  This section contains audio recordings of lectures by several prominent architects and interviews with members of the faculty at the University Of Houston College Of Architecture. Philip Johnson’s lecture is dated October 20, 1953. Frederick Kiesler’s is undated but is probably from the late 1950s. Paul Rudolph’s is undated but appears to have been done in 1961. The interviews are part of a series done by students in Keeland’s Spring 1968 Fourth Year Studio for a student publication called “Zero” (See Keeland collection, Box 33). The original media (reel-to-reel magnetic tapes) have been preserved, but the recordings have been transferred to compact disc for use by patrons.
- Video Recordings, 1989-2000
  In addition to teaching a design studio, in the mid 1990s Keeland taught the course “Introduction to Architecture,” to familiarize first-year students with the issues and personalities of modern architecture. His lectures were an entertaining and opinionated look at architecture through his eyes. This section contains video recordings of many of the lectures. Also included are recordings of the 1989 Keeland roast; Keeland’s 1996 “40 Proof” retrospective lecture; and the 2000 Keeland memorial service at the College of Architecture. All are in the VHS format and were transferred from the Visual Resources Center at the College of Architecture. For some subjects there is more than one lecture. The VRC designated them as part of its “permanent collection,” but later added new lectures by Keeland on some of the same subjects. The following list identifies the date (if known), the lecturer, the subject of the lecture, and its duration.
  - Keeland, Alvar Aalto, 30 minutes, March 12, 1997 (Box 5, Videocassette 1)
  - Keeland, Alvar Aalto, 55 minutes, March 29, 1995 (Box 5, Videocassette 2)
  - Keeland, Charles Moore and Paul Rudolph, 30 minutes, April 9, 1997 (Box 5, Videocassette 3)
  - Keeland, Charles Moore, 64 minutes, undated (Box 5, Videocassette 4)
  - Keeland, Frank Lloyd Wright, 59 minutes, March 5, 1997 (Box 5, Videocassette 5)
  - Keeland, Frank Lloyd Wright, 76 minutes, March 8, 1995 (Box 5, Videocassette 6)
  - Keeland, Louis Kahn, 72 minutes, April 2, 1997 (Box 5, Videocassette 7)
  - Keeland, Louis Kahn, 90 minutes, approximately 1994-1996 (Box 5, Videocassette 8)
  - Keeland, Mies van der Rohe, 62 minutes, April 19, 1995 (Box 5, Videocassette 9)
  - Keeland, Paul Rudolph, 65 minutes, approximately 1994-1996 (Box 5, Videocassette 10)
  - Keeland, Philip Johnson, 59 minutes, April 23, 1997 (Box 5, Videocassette 11)
  - Keeland, Philip Johnson, 62 minutes, approximately 1994-1996 (Box 5, Videocassette 12)
  - Keeland, Africa, 59 minutes, November 30, 1994 (Box 5, Videocassette 13)
  - Keeland, China, 64 minutes, January 29, 1996 (Box 5, Videocassette 14)
  - Keeland, China, 54 minutes, approximately 1994-1996 (Box 6, Videocassette 1)
  - Keeland, England, 72 minutes, November 23, 1994 (Box 6, Videocassette 2)
  - Keeland, France, 68 minutes, approximately 1994-1996 (Box 6, Videocassette 3)
  - Keeland, India, January 25, 1995 (Box 6, Videocassette 4)
  - Keeland, India, 58 minutes, January 22, 1997 (Box 6, Videocassette 5)
  - Keeland, Italy, 55 minutes, November 9, 1994 (Box 6, Videocassette 6)
  - Keeland, Japan, 58 minutes, February 5, 1997 (Box 6, Videocassette 7)
  - Keeland, Japan, Thailand, Singapore, 68 minutes, February 8, 1995 (Box 6, Videocassette 8)
  - Keeland, Left Coast, 74 minutes, September 20, 1995 (Box 6, Videocassette 9)
  - Keeland, Left Coast, 70 minutes, September 4, 1996 (Box 6, Videocassette 10)
  - Keeland, Mexico, 61 minutes, February 26, 1996 (Box 6, Videocassette 11)
  - Keeland, Mexico, 82 minutes, undated (Box 6, Videocassette 12)
  - Keeland, Mexico, Central America, 80 minutes, undated (Box 6, Videocassette 13)
  - Keeland, Mid-America, 74 minutes, September 18, 1996 (Box 6, Videocassette 14)
  - Keeland, Mid-America, 72 minutes, September 25, 1996 (Box 6, Videocassette 15)
  - Keeland, Mid-Europe, 67 minutes, undated (Box 7, Videocassette 1)
  - Keeland, Mid-Left Coast, 64 minutes, September 21, 1994 (Box 7, Videocassette 2)
  - Keeland, Mid-Left Coast, 74 minutes, September 11, 1996 (Box 7, Videocassette 3)
  - Keeland, New York, 63 minutes, October 2, 1996 (Box 7, Videocassette 4)
  - Keeland, New York, 59 minutes, undated (Box 7, Videocassette 5)
  - Keeland, Right Coast, 72 minutes, October 5, 1994 (Box 7, Videocassette 6)
  - Keeland, Right Coast, 67 minutes, January 24, 1996 (Box 7, Videocassette 7)
  - Keeland, Right Coast, 72 minutes, September 26, 1996 (Box 7, Videocassette 8)
  - Keeland, Russia, 59 minutes, November 13, 1996 (Box 7, Videocassette 9)
  - Keeland, Russia, 54 minutes, undated (Box 7, Videocassette 10)
  - Keeland, South America, 59 minutes, February 19, 1997 (Box 7, Videocassette 11)
  - Keeland, South America, 60 minutes, February 22, 1995 (Box 7, Videocassette 12)
  - Keeland, Spain, 65 minutes, February 15, 1995 (Box 7, Videocassette 13)
  - Keeland, Spain, 65 minutes, February 12, 1997 (Box 7, Videocassette 14)
  - Keeland, Texas, 73 minutes, August 28, 1996 (Box 7, Videocassette 15)
  - Keeland, Texas, 73 minutes, approximately 1997 (Box 8, Videocassette 1)
  - Keeland, West Coast, 61 minutes, Fall 1998 (Box 8, Videocassette 2)
  - Keeland, West Coast/Desert, 57 minutes, undated (Box 8, Videocassette 3)
  - Keeland, World, 61 minutes, August 21, 1996 (Box 8, Videocassette 4)
  - Keeland, India, China, Japan, Spain, South America, Spring 1998 (Box 8, Videocassette 5)
  - Keeland, Post-Modernism, undated (Box 8, Videocassette 6)
  - Keeland, Cemeteries, 52 minutes, January 15, 1997 (Box 8, Videocassette 7)
  - Keeland, University of Houston and Howard Barnstone, undated (Box 8, Videocassette 8)
  - Keeland, Mid-Term, 82 minutes, October 16, 1996 (Box 8, Videocassette 9)